<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Techmemos on Bum&#39;s note</title>
    <link>https://daebum.com/techmemo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Techmemos on Bum&#39;s note</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 11:25:32 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daebum.com/techmemo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>대표적인 클라우드 서비스 프로바이더별 솔루션 모음</title>
      <link>https://daebum.com/techmemo/cloud-provider-service-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 11:25:32 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daebum.com/techmemo/cloud-provider-service-solutions/</guid>
      <description>대표적인 클라우드 서비스 프로바이더별 솔루션 모음
Azure Architecture Center
The Azure Architecture Center is the official center for guidance, blueprints, patterns, and best practices for building solutions with Microsoft Azure. It is curated by the Microsoft patterns &amp;amp;amp practices team. Architecture Resources | AWS
Explore a collection of technical resources to help you build more effectively and efficiently in the AWS Cloud, including reference implementations, best practice guides, whitepapers, and architecture diagrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Good Test Cases</title>
      <link>https://daebum.com/techmemo/writing-good-test-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 15:32:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daebum.com/techmemo/writing-good-test-cases/</guid>
      <description>As far as possible, write test cases in such a way that you test only one thing at a time. Do not overlap or complicate test cases. Attempt to make your test cases ‘atomic’. Ensure that all positive scenarios AND negative scenarios are covered. Language:  Write in simple and easy-to-understand language. Use active voice instead of passive voice: Do this, do that. Use exact and consistent names (of forms, fields, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Test Cases Is Important</title>
      <link>https://daebum.com/techmemo/why-test-cases-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 10:34:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daebum.com/techmemo/why-test-cases-is-important/</guid>
      <description>なんでテストケース作成するの :作成する目的は大きく分けますと下記の二つです。
・テスト漏れの防止
・テストの透明化
テスト漏れの防止 ・サービスはユーザーによって想像を超える様々な使い方や入力の仕方が想定されます。 ・テスト担当個人の判断でテスト内容を決めてしまうと、テスト項目のもれが発生し、重大なバグ発生の要因となります。
テストの透明化 ・リリース後にバグが見つかった場合、開発工程でどのようなテストを行ったかが把握できなければ、また一から考えられるテストを繰り返し実施するという無駄な工程が発生することになります。効率的なテストを行うためには、第三者が見てもわかる透明化された状態でテストケースを残しておく必要があります。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>프로젝트에서의 커뮤니케이션</title>
      <link>https://daebum.com/techmemo/project-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 15:15:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daebum.com/techmemo/project-communication/</guid>
      <description>프로젝트 진행에서는 크게 두 가지가 중요  프로덕트 생산활동 (설계/개발/테스트/환경구축) 커뮤니케이션  프로젝트에서의 프로덕트 만들기의 중요성  프로젝트 자체를 진행하기 위한 중요한 요소.  프로젝트에서의 커뮤니케이션의 중요성  의사결정/합의 프로젝트 방향성  테모도리를 줄인다. 프로젝트 전체의 리스크를 줄인다. (잘못된 방향으로 가지 않게)   커뮤니케이션의 종류와 역활 Real time(MTG)
 Daily Weekly Monthly Ad-hoc   Non-Real time
 E-mail
 Slack
  미팅 베스트 프랙스티스  미팅을 하는 목적/골이 참가자 전원 공유되어 있음.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>